My name is Vasily Borisov,
I am the director of master's programs
“Applied Artificial Intelligence” and “Machine Learning Engineering”,
and I'll tell you
about artificial intelligence for science.
Artificial intelligence is a field of computer science
which is engaged in the creation of programs and systems capable of performing tasks,
which usually require human intellectual abilities.
These tasks may include pattern recognition,
natural language processing, planning and decision making.
Artificial intelligence uses methods of machine learning, deep learning,
neural networks and other technologies for data analysis and model creation,
which can imitate human thinking.
The term "artificial intelligence" was coined by John McCarthy
at the Dartmouth Conference back in 1956.
Development of artificial intelligence over the past 70 years
can be divided into several stages.
At the first stages, systems were created
using logical databases and rules.
The second stage began with the advent of machine learning,
At this stage, algorithms were developed
allowing computers to learn from experience and make predictions.
This was followed by the stage of development of deep learning and neural networks,
At this stage, deep learning models were created.
History of the emergence of large language models
begins with the development of simpler models in the 80s and 90s.
However, a real breakthrough in this area
occurred in the late 2010s with the advent of technology
generative pre-trained transformers - such as neural language models,
which are trained on large datasets to generate human-like text.
Currently, the ongoing development and improvement of artificial
intelligence includes deep learning,
natural language processing and computer vision.
There are two types of artificial intelligence:
strong (or general) and weak (or specialized).
Examples of weak artificial intelligence are smart home technologies,
online translators, image recognition systems, and so on.
Weak artificial intelligence is capable of solving only those tasks for which it was created and trained.
For example, a chess program can only play chess.
What distinguishes strong artificial intelligence from weak artificial intelligence is its ability to decide
various tasks, rather than highly specialized ones.
At the moment there is no strong artificial intelligence,
which would be capable of solving a wide range of problems.
Scientists and experts argue about the possibilities and timing of creating artificial intelligence,
representing the integration of already created artificial intelligence systems
into a single system capable
solve humanity's problems.
Rapid development of artificial intelligence technologies
requires control by society and the state.
The Alliance in Artificial Intelligence brings together leading research centers
and technology companies in Russia in order to develop their competencies
and accelerated implementation of artificial intelligence
in education, research and practical business activities.
The main task of the Alliance is to provide technological
leadership of our country in the global high-tech market.
The use of artificial intelligence in science and industry is developing dynamically
and covers all new areas of human life.
This rapid spread of technology causes concern among citizens,
how safe is artificial intelligence for humans,
in which areas it is permissible to use it,
who will be responsible for the actions of artificial intelligence, etc.
Large language models can be used for scientific purposes to solve various problems.
For example, they can be used
for processing large volumes of text data -
such as analysis of scientific articles, patents or medical records.
They can also help in sentiment analysis of the text,
identifying keywords and phrases, as well as identifying plagiarism.
The model in its work receives a “prompt” as input - this is a request from the user or a set of keywords,
and then selects the most suitable next word,
after that, the resulting string is again fed to the input of the model,
and she selects another word.
Using prompts to write texts allows graduate students to better
understand the unique challenges associated with writing scientific papers,
and develop the skills necessary to work effectively in this field.
It should be noted, however,
that one should always use the most modern and advanced technologies available
for you the moment you use them.
There are many different types of prompts,
which can be applied regardless of which language model you are using.
The basic principle is to always start a query with an action verb, for example, “come up with options”
“write”, “analyze” and so on.
Clearly formulate the end goal - the type of content, for example, an analytical article,
description of the schedule or email and subject matter.
You can create complex three-step tasks,
including collecting information, summarizing and creating a final answer.
You can also specify the length of the text (for example, from 400 to 800 characters).
If you don't want to go into detail,
you can simply write: short or long text.
There are several types of scientific tasks that can be automated
using artificial intelligence. For example, classification of articles.
Artificial intelligence can categorize articles
according to various categories such as topic, type of study, year of publication, and so on.
Text analysis: artificial intelligence can analyze the text of an article,
identifying key words, phrases and ideas and their relationships.
Identification of authors: artificial intelligence can determine the authors of an article,
by comparing their writing style to other authors in the database.
Article quality assessment: artificial intelligence can evaluate the quality of the article itself,
analyzing its structure, research quality and results.
You can see the main action verbs on the slide
and try to use them in working with large language models.
Basic principles for creating effective prompts
for artificial intelligence systems include the following aspects.
The first is precision and clarity: requests must be formulated
so clear and precise that the system can understand what exactly is required.
The second is specificity:
requests must be specific and specific to a particular task or situation.
Third, grammatical correctness:
queries must be grammatically correct,
so that the artificial intelligence system can interpret them correctly.
Understandability: queries must be understandable to the artificial intelligence system,
so she can find the information she needs or complete a task.
Optimization:
queries must be optimized
to achieve the best results,
for example, for better efficiency or performance.
And finally, saving resources.
Text generated using artificial intelligence technology
can be easily detected using special tools.
Public text detection services,
generated using large language models are presented on the slide.
But they are also developing rapidly and new ones are appearing.
Academic integrity requires acting ethically and responsibly in the learning process.
and preparation of scientific texts.
It should be remembered that the use of artificial intelligence tools for plagiarism
Forgery, cheating in exams or research will not be tolerated.
Using large language models provides a convenient mechanism
for working with large amounts of information.
But it is worth emphasizing that the use
such tools have only an auxiliary function
and eases the graduate student’s path in preparing their dissertation.
On the other hand, one should not hope
that the use of state-of-the-art methods will replace you and your dissertation work.
The author and only the author is responsible for the final result,
since the use of artificial intelligence technology
when writing text can be easily calculated using special methods.
Thank you for your attention.