Good afternoon, dear listeners.
Today we will get to know you
with digital services
for grant application activity
and some features of this activity.
"Grant" - from the English "gift" - is a targeted financial subsidy,
which is provided to scientists for scientific research.
Grants are allocated from the federal budget,
from the budgets of the constituent entities of the Russian Federation and specialized non-profit funds,
charitable foundations and various international foundations.
One of the largest grant funds
on the territory of the Russian Federation is the Russian Science Foundation.
It is a non-profit organization
created for the purpose of financing and organizational support of scientific activities.
The Russian Science Foundation subsidizes scientific research in a number of areas,
which, in general, cover the main areas of scientific activity.
They are shown on the slide; we will not dwell on them in more detail.
Here is the start page of the information and analytical system
Russian Science Foundation.
It will appear in front of you as soon as you register and enter your username and password.
It contains a number of tabs.
This is information about current or already held competitions in calendar format, and, in fact,
already with the “create request” button active
you can start creating requests right here.
Next is the participant form, which you should definitely fill out, since the information in the application
downloaded from here
that is, this is both personal information and information about the experience of participating in scientific projects,
awards and publications received,
All this must be filled out in this tab, which is called “Questionnaire”.
Next is the “Application” tab, it works, in fact, as an aggregator,
that is, this is the history of your applications, supported or unsupported
as a participant and as a leader.
You can return to it at any time
and look at both the competition documentation,
and, in fact, everything that you stated and promised to the grant fund.
Next, the “Organizations” tab is the organization,
to which you are attached, that is, in our case it is the Ural Federal University,
and you should definitely check this point before submitting your application.
And “Fund Contacts” - information for feedback, information about
where to send a printed version of your application, it is presented on the last tab.
The Next Big Grant Fund
is the Grants Council of the President of the Russian Federation,
which was created for state support of young Russian scientists and leading scientific schools.
The Presidential Grants Council distributes Presidential grants for young scientists,
Presidential scholarships and some personal scholarships
also for young scientists working in certain areas of scientific activity.
Before you is the information and analytical system of the Grant Council of the President of the Russian Federation.
It includes a start page and, in fact, a number of pages that are dedicated to
grant application activities.
The start page provides up-to-date information about current
and completed competitions, also general information and some scientific analytics.
For example, here are the competition participants and various materials,
related to the activities of this fund itself.
Basic information is available to users
who have registered as participants in specific grant competitions.
This is the grant’s personal page, this is contact information, these are questions,
which you can ask technical support,
the history of the grant, in fact, everything you stated,
this is a history of data changes and some instructions about how
how to work with this system, and what you can do, write a review
in order to somehow be able to improve this system.
Let's consider the main stages of the grant application activities of scientists, there are seven of them.
First of all, if you want
To apply for a grant, you must carefully read the competition documentation.
Next - register in the appropriate digital system,
All grant applications today are submitted through the system,
in some cases it is necessary to attach a paper original,
in some cases there is no need for this.
The third stage is creating an application.
It is necessary to write an application in accordance with the competition documentation
and upload it accordingly to the digital service.
Next, the project team is formed in the system and the application is edited.
The sixth step is submitting an application.
And then the application goes through several stages of consideration within the fund,
and the fund publishes a list of winners within the established time frame,
and, in fact, at this stage it will be possible to get acquainted with the results of the competitive selection.
As you can see, the grant application procedure is quite multi-stage,
and each stage requires some effort.
We will look at the main elements of a well-prepared or, as I call it,
good grant application.
It should contain a title page, which should contain the title, authors,
a list of keywords and annotation for your application.
The abstract is what the expert will definitely read first.
It is important to remember that the expert is a very busy person and the abstract is a kind of advertisement according to which,
in general, in the first minutes it will become clear whether your application is a winning one or not,
Therefore, great attention is always paid to writing annotations.
Keywords.
An experienced keyword expert is immediately able to assess the problem and task,
which you designate, and at this stage also make some decisions for yourself.
Information about the manager and main executors of the project.
At this point, please do not forget to praise yourself,
provide a list of your publications, scientific background, some leadership experience
and the completion of previous projects that you and your project team have received awards.
All this will, of course, have a positive effect on the results of consideration of your application.
And the main content of the project, which includes a number of points -
this is a scientific problem that the project aims to solve,
this is, in fact, the problem that your project is intended to solve.
It should be written in sufficient detail, but at the same time succinctly in order to
so that it is clearly clear what your project is aimed at.
As a rule, scientific significance is highlighted as a separate item
and the relevance of solving the identified problem,
that is, what question, what burning topic
affects your project and how it is intended to solve it,
a specific task or tasks within the problem,
which the project aims to solve.
There may be one task, or there may be several,
It is recommended to do from five to seven tasks so that it is clear, in general,
how do you see, among other things, the breakdown of your project into stages.
Scientific novelty of the research and justification for the achievability of the results –
this is a kind of literary review, this is something that already exists
in conjunction with the current state of research, this is point five,
and how exactly your research is different, what new you bring to the scientific community,
what results do you plan to achieve and how new, original and significant are they,
and to what extent, of course, they are achievable within the framework of the project - time and resources.
The next stage is the proposed methods and approaches,
how will you achieve your goal,
what modern scientific methods you will use.
Maybe you offer some of your own original approaches, of course, about this
worth writing in this paragraph.
You should also outline the general work plan for the entire implementation period and the expected results.
A general work plan is sometimes required, broken down by performer
or it may be designated as a schedule.
It is worth noting the scientific groundwork that the research team has
as in the summary, as in the information about the managers,
and in a separate paragraph, briefly, concisely, but at the same time, describe it sufficiently fully.