Good afternoon, dear listeners.
Today we will look at
scientific citation systems
and how to use them to extract
maximum benefit for the dissertation candidate.
The Scientific Citation System is an electronic bibliographic database,
containing some analytical
information about publications,
These include scientific journals, book publications, and patents.
Scientific citation systems are necessary to
to discover scientific works,
as well as evaluate and analyze them,
not only them, but also publications,
and publication activity of authors.
There are international systems
scientific citation, there are two of them,
this is the Web of Science system, owned by the American company Thomson Scientific,
and the Scopus system, owned by the Dutch company Elsevier.
Both of these systems are generally accepted
they publish several thousand scientific papers a year
and therefore are quite complete,
and they are convenient to use for scientific research.
However, today
on the territory of the Russian Federation
direct access to these systems,
unfortunately, it is significantly limited.
In addition, to international bases
scientific citations are not all included
scientific publications published in Russia,
therefore in the Russian Federation there is
own scientific citation database,
it's called eLibrary,
and its developer is
electronic scientific library eLibrary.
There is its own
science citation index,
it's called "Russian"
Science Citation Index".
In addition to articles in scientific journals,
The eLibrary database includes reports at conferences,
monographs, textbooks,
as well as patents and dissertations.
ELibrary solves a number of problems for various
categories of users.
We are interested in you and me
categories of readers and authors.
eLibrary Challenges for Readers
is, in fact, a search for a catalog of magazines,
this is a search by author, subject index and some scientific publishing houses,
about which we can learn, in fact,
using this system.
In addition, for authors
this is Science Index, or scientific index,
my colleagues will tell you about it in more detail,
and this is the Russian Science Citation Index - as the main one. It is assigned to all authors,
who have ever published their work on the territory of the Russian Federation.
So, we are on the start page
scientific electronic library eLibrary.
Here is the site interface,
and we see several tabs with information for different categories of users.
What is useful to readers is, in fact, collections of publications, search queries and groups,
which you can customize for yourself.
For organizations and publishing houses
there is also information
The same information is available for authors - these are instructions on how to register,
it’s like getting your own Science Index and some advice to help young scientists.
What else is important here...
This is, in fact, a literary search.
We can make it happen with you
basic literature search, e.g.
by one or more keywords,
and the search results obtained
somehow analyze
you see that there is an icon,
which means access to the full text.
Some publications are not available
in full text format,
and, let’s say, you can watch them either
on the publisher’s website, or get only some bibliographic information on them.
In addition, you can use the navigator to search, that is, search according to various criteria,
for example, by authors,
you can find your own profile this way
and see the analytics for yourself
or according to other authors,
if you are interested in searching
for this category.
Or configure it initially
extended literature search.
Advanced Literature Search
carried out in several categories,
for example, we are looking for publication type
with the keyword “biosensor”,
when this keyword is only in the title of the publication,
and these, for example, are only scientific articles.
We are already getting significantly less
number of publications, but nevertheless
there are still a lot of them.
To narrow down your search results, you need to be more specific, e.g.
by author's last name or year,
when it is necessary to find the most recent or, conversely, fundamental works.
In general, a literary search is carried out from large to small.
If you are just entering this area,
or if you meet someone