Good afternoon, dear colleagues.
Today we will talk about expert methods of assessment of a scientist's scientific performance.
When may we need an expert assessment?
For example, when applying for a job, when applying for a grant project
or when assessing the performance of a whole structural unit or a small scientific group.
As an example, let's consider the procedure of expert assessment by the Russian Science Foundation,
which occurs when we submit an application for examination.
The procedure is complex and expensive, consists of several stages,
and to carry out such an examination it is necessary at the first stage
to form a pool of experts in subject areas that corresponds to the grant application.
After this there is a formal check
based on characteristics from the competition documentation.
Next, an individual examination takes place,
which involves two to five experts per application.
Each expert writes a resume according of application assessment and fills in the questionnaire.
Applications are then reviewed at a meeting of the expert council section
by scientific areas.
Then applications are selected by expert councils,
are considered at a general meeting of the foundation expert council.
This is a big job, time-consuming, which requires
attracting various scientometric tools.
What means can help in an expert assessment?
Traditionally in this kind of procedures, the Hirsch index is used.
This is the number h, the maximum number h,
where the author publishes at least h articles,
and each of them is cited at least h times.
You can determine the h-factor or Hirsch index according to the graph shown in the slide.
This indicator is useful because at the same time it displays publication activity,
and the scientific authority of the author,which we are considering.
However, it has few drawbacks.
It is impossible to show various aspects of a scientists activity in one number.
This indicator is more profitable for experienced researchers
with a lot of publications and scientific work experience,
H-factor doesn't really suitable for comparing disciplines
with different average levels of citations.
Also for young researchers, for graduate students, the h-factor figure doesn't say much,
since their publications have not yet got enough citations,
It is recommended to young scientists to turn attention, in fact, to the publication process,
and the H-index will increase over time.
Also, the Hirsch index does not reflect the dynamics of a scientific work,
and if at some point in time the scientist stopped working in science,
then his H-index will remain as high or as low
as it was during the process of his work.
For proper accounting of scientific activities we need to carry out normalization,
in particular, comparing the number of citations in various fields of science.
As you can see from the picture on the right, for different subject areas
such as agriculture, biology, education, chemistry, physics,
completely different ratios of the number of published works to
average number of references are characteristic. The tendency to cite older works,
original works or fresh ones, came in recent years also varies.
For normalization, it is common to use percentiles.
Percentile is calculated based on type of publication, that is, for one type of publications
in the same subject category
and for works published in the same years as the work in question.
In the right graph you can see citation count curve
for articles in the field of inorganic chemistry, published in 2015.
A large number of works have small number of citations,
and a small number of works have a number of citations up to 430.
The number of citations is shown on the left axis.
On the right axis the percentile is shown, in which certain works fall into.
For example, if you received 30 citations per publication,
then your article falls into the 89th percentile by citation,
if we received 10 citations on publication - we fall into the 52nd percentile,
that is, 48% of publications have as many or more citations.
An indicator such as percentile allows taking into account the subject area of these publications,
thus allowing you to get rid of some shortcomings of the Hirsch index.
For a more adequate assessment of individual activities of scientists
Clarivate proposed a new type of diagram, which is called Beamplot.
It places the researcher's publications in context
and allows comparing and evaluating citations of his works by year.
This approach allows you to avoid reducing the results to one metric,
and based on the graph shown in the right picture,
you can think and discuss
why do a scientist citations look the way they look.
The vertical axis in the graph reflects date of publication, namely the year of publication.
The horizontal axis shows citation percentile,
and for each year individual publications are displayed by dots.
The dotted line shows median citation value,
that is, the citation percentile that is typical for all publications of the author.
The positive side of this schedule is taking into account the dynamics of publication activity.
For example, in the above graph we see,
that in 2014 the citation number of author's work was lower than in other years.
This chart is very helpful in solving a multiparameter problem
by choosing the best specialist for that or this position, one or another task.
For example, here is a table with the performance of four researchers
in the field of inorganic chemistry,
A, B, C and D - they all have different numbers of citations,
publications, h-index, average percentile and so on.
Naturally, the choice of the best one depends from the problem we are solving.
However, for a correct assessment one should look to
not just the numbers in the table, but also the Beamplot chart.
In particular, if we look simply into numbers, then for researcher A
we have the largest percentage of international works,
we have the highest h-index
and his other indicators are also at the level of other researchers.
However, taking into account the dynamics of publication activity
you can identify gaps in his career
or that he completed his scientific career in certain year.
As an example for researchers C and D are Beamplot charts,
on the basis of which it is possible to see that in 2014-2016
citations of researcher D on average was lower, than the citation rate of the works of scientist C,
however, the number of these works may be the same.
Based on the discussion, which necessarily one should carry out based on the results of constructing Beamplot,
you can select the optimal candidates for employment, for issuing a grant,
to perform a specific scientific task.
Where to find and how to build Beamplot?
The original version of Beamplot was proposedby Clarivate, integrated into Web of Science,
if you log into the system, you can find among researchers your own or someone else's surname,
press the search button, go to the list of researchers and go to your profile.
In particular, here in the first line my researcher profile is shown,
and on this personal page in the right column below
we can see a shortened Beamplot version for the entire history of the scientists work.
The minimum number of citations is shown there, maximum number of citations, percentile
and the median value as a green circle.
But when you click on the link, which is shown by the arrow,
we can move on to a more complete view
and look at the publications of a scientist over the past 10 years
or even throughout his entire career since the 1980s.
So we can look at citation of the scientists works
and the number of these works indexed in Web of Science database for various years,
make one decision or another based on such expert assessment.
What to do if we dont have access to Web of Science
and we can't build the plot automatically?
In this case we have free alternatives.
For example, in the R language a special library BibPlots was developed,
which includes the beamlot function, based on Web of Science-based data,
or on other databases, allows to generate a Beamplot chart.
Alternatively, if you have programming skills,
then using Python and Matplotlib library you can build such a graph yourself,
however, here you have to write a lot of code manually.
Thank you for your attention.