Good afternoon, dear colleagues.
Today we will talk about scientific positioning
universities at the global level.
From the point of view of an outside observer - be
then an applicant, an administrator of another university,
a simple man in the street - the quality and level of the university
determined by international
university rankings,
which exist in different countries.
Key positioning factors
universities in these rankings are
quality of research, that is
quantity and quality of publications,
citation level, results that
are transformed into technologies and developments,
the international cooperation.
The higher the percentage of international
collaboration between university scientists,
as well as international exchange programs
indicate the high level of the university.
Academic reputation is determined by
based on surveys of experts in a similar field.
Academic reputation is determined based on
surveys of academic experts and employers,
lists of which annually
are formed by universities,
are sent to international rankings
agencies for conducting surveys.
In their questionnaires, experts can indicate
which universities do they consider the most
prestigious and authoritative.
Based on similar responses and
international ratings are being formed.
And finally, an important role is played
funding and its volume for each university.
Funding evidence
about the level of the university and trust
from foundations and government
and private organizations.
The most famous are
three international ratings.
These are the ratings published
international agencies
(such as Quacquarelli Symonds), magazines
(such as Times Higher Education)
or other organizations (like Chinese
Shanghai Ranking, also called ARWU).
Ratings are based on
evaluation of universities according to criteria,
which were listed earlier.
For each specific rating, a list
criteria and their weights vary slightly.
That is, for the QS rating the highest
academic reputation carries weight,
reputation among employers,
ratio of employees and
students and specific citations,
and for the Shanghai rating the main
the criteria are the quality of education,
quality of teaching
composition and research results and others.
For each of the three listed ratings
in its part, subject ratings are formed
by subject areas
development of science and technology.
As an example, here are
results of Russian universities
in the QS World University Rankings
in terms of engineering and technology.
On the right is the score obtained from
indicators given on the previous slide,
and as a result of sorting
according to the specified total score
we get a university place
in the overall international ranking.
As you can see, Moskovsky is in the lead here
state university with 57 places,
a Ural Federal University
Not here in this category.
Although in other categories (for example,
chemistry, physics, materials science)
Ural University takes pride of place.
By the QR code on the right you can find
general list of subject areas,
by which the ranking is made
by Quacquarelli Symonds.
If we take the Shanghai rating
and a slightly different subject area,
namely the field of mathematics, then in the latter
line in the category “400-500 place”,
in the category from 401 to 500th place we
we will see the Ural Federal University,
since the results of his research,
graduate employment results
and other parameters allowed
him to take such a place.
Here for the big places, above
hundreds total score is unknown,
therefore, only a cohort or list is given
places where the university is located.
You can also find the QR code on the right
a complete list of subject areas,
by which the ranking is made.
What's in Russia?
There are also several ratings in Russia.
As an example, here is the RAEX rating,
however, there are others such
like the Interfax rating,
Forbes magazine and other publications and organizations.
It is for RAEX that the criteria are
receiving quality education,
level of demand
graduates by employers
and the level of research activity.
Universities are also analyzed
in different thematic areas -
from agriculture to technical sciences.
Often cultural organizations in the area
cultures do not always fall into such ratings.
Here is a list of universities
included in the Russian RAEX rating
and those who took first place up to tenth,
on which the Uralsky is located
Federal University.
On the right is the overall score according to the rating criteria.
However, due to the large
number of Russian ratings
(you can see a list of them on this slide)
aggregate ratings appeared,
which give some general rating
according to the list of special ratings.
In particular, there is a National
aggregate ranking of universities,
which is considering hundreds of universities
Russia from a list of twelve ratings.
As a result of calculating the overall indicator
based on the results of individual
ratings are formed in several leagues.
The Premier League includes 50 universities
(as they call it - “Top 50”),
the first league is “Top 100” and so on.
And leagues six to nine
and a tenth are in the alarm zone.
If the university is included in these leagues,
it has alarmingly low rates
and must carry out active work
to improve your performance.
Unfortunately, this is not the case in Russian ratings yet.
division by subject areas is common.
However, you can filter, for example,
universities by affiliation
to one or another ministry
or this or that industry.
What needs to be done to promote
scientific and technical results of universities
in international and Russian ratings?
Teams within universities, including
Ural Federal University,
a strategy for effective
promotion according to all criteria,
including research results, alumni,
international interaction and
interaction with enterprises.
It is necessary to monitor the use of social
networks, especially official accounts,
issue press releases regularly and
interact with scientists in academic networks,
it is necessary to transfer knowledge and
participate in social events,
be an active actor in this direction
and also actively interact both with society,
so with politicians for promotion
their results and their universities.
We wish good luck to our University
in promotion in scientific rankings!
Thank you.