Good afternoon, dear graduate students and young scientists!
My name is Telepaeva Daria,
I am the Chairman of the Council
young scientists of our University,
candidate of sociological sciences and
Associate Professor of the Department of Sociology and Technology
state and municipal administration.
As part of today's lecture, I would like you
talk about the measures to support young scientists,
youth science that exist in
our region, in the Sverdlovsk region,
as well as about those support measures that
available only at our University.
And I'll start with an important scholarship,
which is paid regularly
has been paid for many years
and is available to both graduate students and
and all categories of students.
And I'm talking about scholarship
Governor of the Sverdlovsk region.
To receive this scholarship you must
should only study for “excellent” grades.
That is, even one “four” is already
ineligibility for this scholarship.
In addition to excellent academic performance, you must have
outstanding abilities in
educational and scientific activities,
you can either be a winner
Olympiads or creative competitions,
if this direction suits you and
matches your field of study.
You may have patents, scientific articles in leading
scientific or Russian or foreign publications,
you can have different performances
at scientific conferences and so on,
that is, all your achievements,
that you can brag about
precisely as a young scientist, as a graduate student,
who has behind him
already a certain background.
Amount of this scholarship
is 1,500 rubles. monthly,
it is paid within one academic period
year, that is, assigned to you from September 1.
And until August 31st throughout the academic year
you are the recipient of this scholarship.
It is important to note that this scholarship
is paid to you only once,
that is, you will not receive
1,500 rub. every month,
you will receive 18,000 rubles immediately for all 12 months.
And if you want to apply next year
application for this scholarship,
then you will have to go through the competitive procedures again
and re-prepare the application
those existing scientific achievements,
which you have, and go through this competition again.
The next scholarship that is available to everyone
graduate students, all students of the Sverdlovsk region,
is the first President's scholarship
Russia of Boris Nikolaevich Yeltsin.
It also implies that you
study only for “excellent” grades
and you have outstanding abilities
in educational and scientific activities,
they are absolutely similar here, as for
scholarships from the governor of the Sverdlovsk region.
The amount of this scholarship is 4,000 rubles.
monthly, it is paid immediately for a year,
but you get these payments
only once a semester,
that is, once every six months at a time
24,000 rubles will arrive.
both in the first and second semester.
And if you want next year
also apply for this scholarship,
then you will also have to
new to take part in this competition,
since the scholarship is paid
only for one academic year.
Another important support measure
which is available to our young scientists,
is the Governor's Award
Sverdlovsk region for young scientists.
In order to receive this award,
you must have outstanding
achievements in the field of science and technology,
which are confirmed by various
publications, patents,
participation in leading scientific conferences
and various other ways.
The prize is awarded to the young
a scientist who is not yet 35 years old,
and it is awarded annually in 22 categories.
The size of each award is 200,000 rubles.
That is, once a year the Governor personally from his own hands
presents a prize to twenty-two young scientists.
And it is very prestigious,
a very serious reward,
which, indeed, opens up many
opportunities for you as a young scientist.
Another support measure that
available only to students at UrFU,
is an increased state
academic scholarship
for achievements in
research activities.
This scholarship is unique
it is only available to students
at the Ural Federal University, in others
There are no such scholarships at universities.
In order to receive it, you must
firstly, study on a budget basis
and, secondly, in full-time education,
you must, of course, have basic academic
scholarship and scientific achievements.
The amount of this scholarship varies,
it depends on personal rating
and ranges from 3,000 to 15,000 rubles. monthly.
It is important to understand that the application for this
The scholarship is submitted through your personal account.
More information you
you can find out by clicking on the QR code,
and get acquainted there with
all detailed instructions.
But to put it briefly, then
you are in your personal account
fill out an application for this scholarship,
fill out all accompanying forms,
attach your publications, certificates,
which guarantee your
speaking at scientific conferences,
and various other scientific achievements of yours.
All this is sent to the moderators.
Moderators are checking your
application and either it is accepted,
or they reject it in order to
you need to make some changes.
And, if your application is accepted,
then she gets into the general competition.
And depending on how many points you scored
It is your application that will award the scholarship.
The size, again, varies from
3,000 to 15,000 rub. monthly.
And another measure of support,
which is also unique
and which was introduced relatively recently,
is a competition of scientific grants for young
scientists from the Ural Federal University.
Who can apply for this competition?
These are, of course, young scientists in
up to 35 years of age inclusive.
In addition, you must be employed
at our University for a scientific position
at main place of work
by no less than 0.25 bets.
Allowed in this competition
participation of scientific teams,
as well as in all support measures,
which I have already talked about.
These are teams of no more than three people, and each
this team must be no more than 35 years old,
you must have publications on project topics
in leading Russian or foreign
peer-reviewed scientific publications and journals.
The amount of such a grant is
from 100,000 to 300,000 rub.
This grant is given for six months.
As a rule, the competition takes place in May, and until
the end of the calendar year, that is, until December
you should already report on your results,
based on what was received within
this grant, this competition.
Why do these grants even exist?
For you to do a little research
and based on this research we could
submit an application to the Federal Science Foundation,
it could be like Russian scientific
foundation and other organizations
who are engaged in grant activities.
Moreover, all recipients of these grants for
young scientists at UrFU must submit such an application.
That is, after your
the project within UrFU has ended,
you undertake, undertake this
obligation to submit an application within a year
already to the Federal Science Foundation
and get, try at least
least get a more serious grant.
This will allow you to continue to study
the topic you have chosen for yourself
and which you see as promising and
corresponding to all those directions
Strategies for scientific and technological development,
which I talked about in the first lecture.
Dear graduate students - young scientists
Ural Federal University!
In this lecture I told
you about those support measures,
that exist in our
region and at our University.
For more detailed information you can always
find out on the UrFU website in the “Science” section
or on the youth science portal
Ural Federal University.