Hello!
Today we will talk about
what is IMRAD format,
what is research
article in IMRAD format,
namely about the logical structure
and the contents of each section.
What is the IMRAD format?
and why lately
many Russian magazines
is it used?
The fact is that this is a very convenient format
presentation of scientific information.
He introduces himself, is often depicted
metaphorically in the form of an hourglass,
when, look, the information, the logic of presenting it...
First, some general information is given,
information in the “methods” and “results” section
is given specifically within the framework of this study,
and then the process happens
the reverse, let's say, funnel,
when the results obtained are interpreted,
they are given broader meanings,
and then the conclusion is given.
And this abbreviation IMRAD -
it entered the Russian language,
but its meaning is essentially this:
this is an introduction,
methods – methods,
results, “R” is the letter in the abbreviation
- these are the results
and finally, discussion –
this is a discussion of the results.
The letter “A” is, in fact, the conjunction and.
This is the format... He received
distribution and development,
In general, it went through a very long evolution,
because from the very beginning,
when science was born
no one wrote in IMRAD format,
and did not follow such logic,
because scientists exchanged
letters in the form of essays,
in the form of some thoughts.
And so it is attributed to Louis Pasteur,
in fact, championship.
This has not been proven, but it appears
that it was he who started this logic
include in your articles,
and therefore gave shape to this format.
In the 70s, the IMRAD format began
actively develop, mainly
in the English-language domain of scientific publication,
scientific communications,
and initially it was medicine, physics, chemistry,
that is, such empirical sciences.
But, of course, even more rapid development
he receives in 1972,
when it was secured
in the US national standard,
This is basically an analogue
to our GOSTs.
And after that, already in the 80s we see
that many magazines around the world accept it
as a standard, prescribed
in the instructions for authors
in various fields of science and technology.
What is happening in Russia?
In Russia there was a slightly unbalanced development,
and originally the IMRAD format
developed in the following areas:
like physics, I already mentioned, and chemistry, of course,
but already in the 10s, in 2010 and today
we see that it is becoming simply ubiquitous
in Russian magazines, used everywhere,
even in areas where he, in general,
may not have always been used before,
for example, in the field of pedagogy.
Many modern magazines, Russian, for example,
magazine, "Integration of Education" -
you can see that they are clearly
adhere to this format.
Why? In fact, this format
has a huge number of advantages.
because if we know how
the information in this article is presented,
It's very easy for us to extract it,
because when we are ready,
what if we are interested
namely research methods,
we'll open the methods section and see
How reliable were the methods?
and, accordingly, were
reliable results were obtained.
Accordingly, it is simplified
and speeds up the review process,
because reviewers don't have to
every time to delve into the logic of presentation,
and, accordingly, accelerates
circulation of scientific information,
the so-called transfer of scientific knowledge.
The process of writing scientific articles
becomes less labor intensive.
And this is a huge problem for many - especially
beginner scientists write a scientific article.
And those graduate students, my graduate students,
who came to me
many of them said that we were going into science
study physics and chemistry,
and in the end we turned out to be writers,
and indeed it is.
But this format makes it easier
process of writing a scientific article,
and in the end we see that scientific knowledge,
of course it's circulating today
much more efficient
than it was 60 years ago.
Let's take a closer look
for each section,
and I draw your attention to the fact that
that some sections of the article are in IMRAD format
already more formalized
and very highly structured.
Among them we will carefully look
to "Introduction" and "Methods".
In the "Results" section
and “Discussion of results”
such a strict logic of presentation, of course,
no and cannot be, but, nevertheless,
this is precisely the “Introduction” section - this is very today
already formalized style and logic of presentation.
The purpose of this section is to answer the question:
Why was the study done at all?
who did what before?
Formulate the problem, that is, find
This is a small gap in scientific knowledge,
which was not covered by previous works,
describe goals and objectives
and, in the end, give a general