Good afternoon.
Today we are discussing topic number 10 of our course,
which is called “Research Ethics in the Digital Age.”
My name is Ivanov Alexey Olegovich, I am a Doctor of Physical and Mathematical Sciences,
Professor, Deputy Vice-Rector for Science, Ural Federal University.
At the same time, I head the Certification Council of the Ural Federal University
and I have been a member of the Higher Attestation for the fifth year
commission of the Russian Federation, that is, I am deeply immersed
in all documentary procedures, regulations related to the preparation,
defense and approval of dissertations, including dissertations for competition
scientific degree of Candidate of Sciences, and Doctor of Sciences, of course, too.
The Ural Federal University has the right to independently award academic degrees,
and we work according to this Regulation.
This is the title page of the Regulations on the award of academic degrees
at the Federal State Autonomous Educational Institution
higher education "Ural
federal university
named after the first president of Russia Boris Nikolaevich Yeltsin."
Several dozen other universities and institutes and academies of sciences in our country have such rights.
And there is a lot of confusion here,
which has, generally speaking, been present in our academic community for the last few years.
The fact is that for some reason many people believe that UrFU awards its own degrees
similar to PhD degrees,
which are awarded, for example, in Europe.
This is completely wrong.
Ural Federal University awards
state academic degrees, we are simply given the right to create ourselves
dissertation advice based on
relevant regulatory documents
(in particular, we have the Regulations on the dissertation council)
and carry out defense procedures ourselves, conduct examinations ourselves,
make the award themselves without seeking consent or consideration
relevant documents in the Higher Attestation Commission.
Moreover, all documents on academic degrees,
awarded to UrFU are necessarily loaded into the Unified Information System
state scientific certification and are constantly monitored by representatives of the Russian Ministry of Education and Science.
But, in this regard, we will, of course, first of all, talk about the problems
related to dissertation research, more precisely with what problems arise,
including ethical ones, during defenses.
This is an extract, a “piece” from our Regulations on the awarding of academic degrees, in which it is written
the main criteria that dissertations for academic degrees must meet.
Each word highlighted here has a separate meaning.
You can’t read them so slantedly in these documents, like “the main
I understood”, the main content. Here
every word has meaning.
Look here: “the dissertation must be written by the author independently.”
Here an element of ethics already arises, and an element of such
debatable and pretentious, you can already make a claim
here to present for some dissertations.
Further: “it must contain new
scientific results and provisions,
who come forward for public defense.”
The novelty of scientific results and provisions is almost the most basic position.
Further: “the dissertation must demonstrate personal contribution”,
that is, independent and personal contribution, naturally
these are related things, this is also an element of ethics and an element that may cause some claims
to how the dissertation is defended and what is being defended.
Now, it is absolutely obvious that it is impossible to write a dissertation without using sources.
Moreover, they definitely must be, and a lot of them,
they must demonstrate mastery of the dissertation
the current state of research in the field of knowledge in which he works.
But, as a rule, this refers to the overview chapter
or overview paragraphs in each chapter if they are written that way.
That is, it should be an overview of the current state of research,
review of modern techniques,
if experimental or some sociological techniques are used.
But, when a review of works is used and conducted (naturally, this is a review of the works of other authors),
There must be links to the authors and the source of borrowings.
Further. Very often, publications that reflect the main content
the main materials of the dissertation, they were published in co-authorship.
A rather subtle question arises here:
What are the rights of each co-author to the material that is published?
That is, is it possible, for example, the same scientific result,
published in the same article, used in several dissertations.
To avoid this problem,
sometimes right in the article somewhere at the end it states the contents,
that is, which of the co-authors contributed what to this article.
For example, one prepared samples in experimental work,
another carried out measurements, a third processed these measurements,
the fourth was looking for some kind of chemical, physical, biological, sociological,
the economic substance of these results, and so on.
If this is not done, then, of course, the issue here is very delicate.
And this question, unfortunately, quite often leads to conflict situations.
We must try to avoid them.
Now, here's what I was saying, it's partially stated here: the ethics of co-authorship.
Now, I have just spoken about the division of scientific results.
Unfortunately, this is not done often, but in general, I would like to recommend
do this right at the entrance so that it is clearly written,
and this must be written down in the text of the dissertation, without fail!
If partially co-authored texts are used,
generally speaking, all co-authors must agree
to use these texts because it is a joint
intellectual property and everyone, generally speaking, has equal rights.
Very often, publications are published in collaboration with a scientific supervisor.
In general, this is probably correct
because after all, it is the scientific director,
as a rule, sets the topic of research, determines some basic positions,
main milestones of this study, research methods.
And I'm not even talking about other co-authors, especially in experimental studies,
who do a lot - samples, installations, etc.
And here, of course, you also have to understand every time,
that the dissertation candidate uses materials from joint research,
and therefore he must distinguish very clearly,
what is his contribution, his own contribution, to this work.
It is often said that the order of co-authors of a publication is important.
This is a moot point.
Generally speaking, there are no uniform guidelines.
For example, there are large scientific teams in which co-authors are located simply
in alphabetical order, according to the first letter of your last name,
and sometimes, sometimes very often, for example,
scientific supervisor of the entire team (this is very often present abroad),
he is always listed as the last co-author.
Sometimes the first co-author is listed as the person who made the main contribution to the article.
But here, too, there are no mandatory, I would say, requirements,
because very often it depends on what traditions have developed in the scientific team,
and if somewhere, someone, sometime insists on the fact that the dissertation author does not have a single publication,
where he is the first co-author, then, actually,
this cannot be a basis for reproach that he violated some ethical things
or took away some other results. Of course not.
Very often, when writing a dissertation text, employees
people use materials that they have written before,
pieces of your own text from your own scientific articles are used.
If these are their own pieces, there is probably no crime here, this is probably
you can do it, but it’s still better not to abuse it
for the simple reason that now all dissertation texts are required to pass
digital check for incorrect borrowings.
And again, if publications have a large team;
and some gratitude is expressed (best done in a dissertation
also reflected in the abstract), there is nothing here that would cause
unhealthy interest of others, well, the author is grateful to those
who helped him in these studies.
But it is important that all scientific novelty and scientific results belong to the author.
Now regarding citing other people's works.
There are several important aspects here. In particular, there must be a very precise quotation,
so that it does not cause... so that incorrectness and inaccuracy
did not raise any doubts that something, somewhere a person is trying to use
some other people's data and at the same time confuses the traces, as they say.
Again, in some sciences
(for example, in literary criticism) one cannot do without extensive quotations from literary sources,
but they must be clearly identified: they must be indicated by quotation marks,
it must be clearly written - from which work,
not just a work, but when it is published, it is a work.
If it's a book, it may have several editions,
that is, this bibliographic citation should be as accurate as possible.
But you still need to understand that the entire dissertation
cannot consist only of borrowed sources.
Very often this, for example,
the work of people who use many experimental setups is faulty,
because they describe experimental techniques.
There are many experimental setups and techniques; these techniques are used from some
there are enough standard descriptions and regulations, and they are half the dissertation, if not more,
capable of borrowing. But this is not the point, of course, because the methods need to be described,
but, in general, you can, as they say, partially use your own vision of these techniques.
Secondly, if you spent more than half of your dissertation describing the methodology, then the question arises:
and where then are your own scientific results, novelty?
The most important thing is to emphasize the novelty.
The novelty of scientific results is the most important thing, this is the thing
which under no circumstances should give rise to doubt
neither from expert councils, nor from expert groups,
neither from opponents, nor from members of dissertation councils.
Now regarding borrowing and all these things,
which I just talked about.
For at least 10 years, maybe more, our country has had a mandatory rule:
that all dissertations must pass a digital borrowing test, the so-called “Anti-plagiarism”.
Although this is not necessarily “Anti-plagiarism”, there are different digital checking systems.
At our university, for example, we use the Rucontext system.
In general, by and large, this is the same thing.
No, I said it wrong, it’s not the same thing, but it’s a very similar system.
What are they checking?
They check the Internet, all the literature that is posted on the Internet
necessarily through the Network, they check through matches of blocks, directly blocks of texts,
they provide information about the volume of borrowings, either in pages or as a percentage of text.
Some systems can, generally speaking,
and check these very relevant texts in a foreign language.
For example, this is what one of the pictures looks like on the right:
here's where, look, three are indicated: original fragments - 77%,
citation – 14, borrowings detected.
What is the difference between a citation and a detected borrowing?
A citation is a piece of text that clearly states where it came from,
from which work is this piece of text taken and should be clearly described
the meaning of this quotation, why it is quoted.
If this is a literary source, then it is clear, it means that this is some kind of necessary content,
if this is some kind of, I don’t know, wise phrase or some kind of conclusion from the work,
some kind of physical, chemical or something else,
The text should also describe what the purpose of using this quotation is.
If this is a review of the novelty of scientific results,
this means an overview of the current state of research,
the so-called introductory overview chapter or overview paragraph,
it should also clearly state that such and such authors conducted such and such a study,
Here they showed such and such results,
such and such samples were studied or something like that.
In part, these systems are able to recognize attempts to bypass.
As a participant, as a member of the Higher Attestation Commission, I have repeatedly participated
in meetings of the Presidium of the Higher Attestation Commission dedicated to appeals made
representatives of the Dissernet group regarding borrowings.
The fact is that borrowings, for example, are of the following nature:
a large piece of text is taken and a contextual replacement is made in it,
for example, somewhere, something agricultural, suppose
where a livestock farm is replaced by a poultry farm
(well, excuse me, it’s kind of a banal example, maybe).
Everything else is the same, one word changes,
one concept, and then the whole text, all the content is the same.
Here are the modern “Atiplagiarism” systems, that’s what we’ll call them in quotes,
Generally speaking, they also know how to distinguish such things.
The most important thing here is the following:
Of course, it is impossible to do without borrowings and citations.
Borrowing is when you simply take some pieces of text that have already been published,
and insert it into your work.
Then the question arises: where, from what sources are they taken?
Anti-plagiarism systems and digital verification systems can recognize these sources
and they just give out a huge list of these same sources,
where did the pieces of text included in the dissertation come from?
So, it’s very important here what these pieces are,
because usually (very often) these pieces appear
from their own articles, from their own reviews, preprints,
reports that were published somewhere earlier and ended up on the Internet.
But if they belong to the author or were made with the participation of the author,
this is one song, there is one attitude towards it, and if these are completely alien pieces,
and, God forbid, these alien pieces are inserted there,
where there is a description of scientific results and scientific conclusions, this is the reason for
so that this work comes under investigation as to whether there is any scientific novelty in it,
But is it an independent work like I showed on the very first slide,
Is there a personal contribution from the author here, or is this all done at his order by someone there?
from somewhere there using the example of his own research.
All this must be avoided.
And Ural Federal University,
and his dissertation committees use
all these methods and, generally speaking, check all these works, trusting, of course,
to our dissertation councils.
And so that the dissertation author does not have any problems in
that there are doubts about scientific novelty, about personal contribution,
You should try to write your dissertation as independently as possible.
It is necessary that the scientific results there be new.
Nobody requires a Ph.D. dissertation.
level of scientific results at the level of the Nobel Prize, but they are still
must be new, interesting and important.
Good luck to you all, goodbye, thank you!