Hello, dear graduate students.
My name is Anna Petrovna Bagirova.
I am a professor, doctor of economics
and candidate of sociological sciences
and occupy an administrative position of
Deputy Director for Science
Institute of Economics and Management and
School of Government Management
and entrepreneurship of the Ural
Federal University.
Today we will talk about
an important topic for every graduate student
publication activity and journal selection
to present results
of their dissertation research.
The first part of this topic is related to publications
from the List of the Higher Attestation Commission,
which exists under the Ministry of Science
and higher education of the Russian Federation.
Issues of choosing publications
platforms for presenting results
of a dissertation research is regulated
by "Regulations on awarding scientists
degrees" at our university.
If your defense is planned in
some other university
which acts independently
the right to award academic degrees,
then you need to familiarize yourself with
their local regulations.
If your defense is planned
in the dissertation council,
existing under the Higher Attestation Commission
in a university without independent right
to award degrees,
then, accordingly, you need to
read the document,
which is called "Regulations
on the awarding of academic degrees"
by the Ministry of Science and Higher
education of the Russian Federation.
Our "Regulations on the awarding of academic degrees"
provides the following important points.
Firstly, it states that
the main scientific results should be
published in publications of a certain level.
These are peer-reviewed scientific publications
and/or peer-reviewed scientific publications,
included in international abstracts
databases and citation systems.
Secondly (and here there is a significant connection with
ministry regulations), it states that
the requirements for these peer-reviewed publications
and the rules for forming their list are established
by Ministry of Science and Higher
education of the Russian Federation.
This is very important because it means
that you as graduate students who are most likely
will defend themselves in dissertation councils,
operating at the Ural Federal University,
should first of all pay attention
to the list of the Higher Attestation Commission, to the list,
which is published by
Ministry of Science and Higher
education of the Russian Federation.
And the third point, which regulates
number of publications required
To submit your dissertation for defense:
today the number of these publications is
at least three for both the subjects
of humanities, social sciences and
natural and technical sciences, while
there must be at least one publication
in a publication included in international
abstract databases and citation systems.
I repeat that this is the Regulation
valid today. Follow all the changes
(and they can even happen
soon)
yourself as a graduate student to ensure that
you don't end up
working on a dissertation
with some unfulfilled set of
requirements for publication activity.
The next important question is
(it worries graduate students a lot)
where the main scientific results should be
published,
and where can I get it and see it?
Here is the current list.
We have already said that the list
peer-reviewed scientific publications
compiled by the Higher Attestation Commission
Ministry of Science and Higher
education of the Russian Federation.
Secondly, this list is linked
to scientific specialties.
And here many questions arise,
if you suddenly change a scientific specialty
during your graduate studies
or at their end.
And one more important point is that
this list is constantly updated.
Accordingly, at any given time
you need to understand
where to find
current version of this list,
and what specialty is that journal associated with,
in which you plan to publish.
We'll look at this clearly at the
website of the Higher Attestation Commission.
Now we will go to the site
Higher Attestation Commission
and see where to find the current lists of publications
included by the Higher Attestation Commission.
It's located here in the tab
"Documents", and then "Reviewed publications".
The list is opened. Here you see
several lists,
we only need the latest, most relevant one.
Now I see that the most relevant one is
this is as of December 19, 2023.
And if we go into this
list, then we'll just see
that, firstly, it is huge,
1235 pages in this document alone
and, accordingly, about 3,000 sources.
And the second thing we see is that this list
contains publications in the context of scientific specialties.
It is important for you to pay attention to
from what time these specialties
have begun to relate to this magazine,
that is, we always choose
latest date match.
It is also important that these specialties,
their association with journals changes periodically.
For example, let's take a specific journal
and let's see how it goes when
Scientific specialties change.
Let's look at the journal "Management Issues".
Here it is shown what publications does it accept today
in the context of three scientific specialties.
Among these, three are economic specialties,
This is "Economic Theory"
"Regional and industry
Economics" and "Management"
and one specialty in sociology -
"Social structure,
social institutions and processes."
If we look at the List
publications of the Higher Attestation Commission for earlier years,
for example, not on December 19, 2023,
and at the end of December 2020
and let's see what were there
specialties of this journal,
then we see that the set of
specialties is completely different.
There are only two economic specialties here,
one specialty is sociology,
and completely different than now, and
one in political science.
If we turn to the same journal,
but in the 2018 List, we will see
that this list did not contain any
connection to scientific specialties,
only to branches of science.
Accordingly, if your article in this journal
was published in 2018, then it
will be counted as an article,
meeting today's requirements
when you submit a dissertation for defense
If your article was published in this
joural in 2020, then it will be credited to you
as a publication result only if
you are defending thesis by one
of these four specialties
or in those new specialties,
which they moved to.
If you are defending thesis and have published
in this magazine in 2023, then, accordingly,
you need to be guided by the 2023 year list
and that set of specialties,
which are currently in this magazine.
So it makes the transition
from specialty to specialty difficult,
because when changing specialty
it is necessary to revise completely those publications
in which your scientific results
have been published,
and it may turn out that the publications you have
will not be enough to obtain a degree.
Recently, all the journals
that belong to the List of Higher Attestation Commissions,
have been classified into three categories.
This has happened in December 2022
when the Higher Attestation Commission first announced
the upcoming changes to regulations
in the field of state scientific certification,
related to the categorization of journals.
Accordingly, today the list
of the Higher Attestation Commission
is divided into three categories,
and it looks something like this:
as shown in this slide.
Next to each journal name
its category is indicated.
Accordingly, the first category is for
the journals of the highest level.
And the third category consists of
lower level journals.
We are now awaiting new criteria
for applicants for academic degrees,
where this categorization of journals
will be taken into account.
That is, these will be the criteria
who will set the
minimum threshold requirements for publication
activity of graduate students coming to the defense.
But now we can say
that the higher the level
and the higher the category of journals, in
which your work was published:
your scientific results,
presented in the dissertation,
the more chances you have to defend
your work on the dissertation committee.
Now I'm on the website of the Higher Attestation Commission
I will demonstrate
where you can find the categorization of the
journals included in the list of Higher Attestation Commissions.
Most recently on the site of the
Higher Attestation Commission
the final journals distribution has appeared
the List of Higher Attestation Commission in three categories.
It can be found here in "Documents" section,
Next we go to "Reviewed Editions" and "Final
distribution of journals on the List of Higher Attestation Commission".
You see that all the journals
here they are evenly separated by colors,
first category journals come first,
then the journals of the second category
and the third category.
Total about 3,000 publications
are classified.
In addition, on the HAC website today there is
information about what categories of publications
are assigned to journals
indexed in Web of Science and Scopus
and other foreign specialized
scientific citation databases.
This document can be used right now.
And please note that in this document
nothing is said about conference proceedings,
which are indexed in Web of Science and Scopus.
According to modern relevant documents
these publications are not equivalent
to categories K1, K2 or K3.
What scientific results are the main ones?
which should be published in journals
from the List of Higher Attestation
Commission or others equivalent to them?
These are, of course, the provisions
which are being defended
as a result of your dissertation work.
It's better to plan all this in advance, at the stage
when you are just starting work on your dissertation,
it's good to have such a preliminary
project of your scientific results.
Of course, without a scientific supervisor
you can't plan it,
but the first scientific result, for example, is desirable,
to be published in
one publication of the Higher Attestation Commission,
the second result - in another and the third - in the third.
We know that today's minimum of
publications is three
This is the minimum threshold for publication activity
for a graduate student defending his dissertation.
This publication activity plan
maybe more detailed
it can be discussed with your supervisor
literally at one of the first meetings,
when you are just creating a table of contents,
this is the plan for your dissertation
research, and it may already be laid there,
that some result stated
in the form of one paragraph or another,
will result in this or that article in journals
from the List of the Higher Attestation Commission.
The plan may, of course, be
detailed with time,
that is, years can be indicated there at once,
months of even submitting your texts,
your manuscripts to the editors of these journals.
This tighter planning
actually makes the work of a graduate student easier,
allows you to better control this work,
adjust it somehow
and pass certification for graduate students,
which, as you know, periodically
included in your curriculum.
So to sum up the
review of publication activity
in journals from the Higher Attestation Commission List, one can
give some recommendations for you
on preparing manuscripts for publications from this List.
The first and very important thing is that
what needs to be checked regularly
check the current List of journals
Higher Attestation Commission
before sending the manuscript,
because this list is constantly
changing, we already told about this today.
Secondly, it is necessary to monitor changes in
regulatory documentation - these are also local acts
of Ural Federal University, and
acts of a higher level, in particular
Ministry of Science and Higher
education, because, as we know,
they regulate what is necessary
number of publications and their level.
Third, you need to choose carefully,
be very careful when choosing a journal
taking into account, of course, the recommendations
from your scientific supervisor,
but also taking into account the categorization of journals.
Four, you need to comply clearly with the
requirements for the structure and design of the text,
take into account the deadlines for reviewing manuscripts in publications
(and they can be very large,
up to a year or more).
And it is important to consider issues of co-authorship
so that this publishing activity of yours
was indeed recognized for
submitting your dissertation for defense.
This will be discussed in more detail
in a special topic in our course.