Good afternoon, dear graduate students, young
scientists from the Ural Federal University!
My name is Daria Telepaeva.
I am the Chairman of the Council
young scientists of our university,
candidate of sociological sciences
and Associate Professor of the Department of Sociology
and technologies of state
and the municipal administration of our university.
Today I would like to tell you about this
an interesting and important topic for all young scientists,
as support for our activities with you,
support for youth science.
And today, as part of this lecture
we will discuss the federal level,
that is, what the authorities do
throughout our country,
and those support measures that
apply to all graduate students,
for all young scientists of the Russian Federation.
So, let's begin.
The very first support measure mentioned
today I would like to tell you,
these are Presidential scholarships and
Government of the Russian Federation.
In order to receive this scholarship,
you must have outstanding abilities
in educational and scientific activities,
you can be the winner of various
Olympiads, creative competitions,
if you are studying in the relevant specialties,
you must be the authors
discoveries, patents, inventions,
you should also have
mandatory scientific articles
in leading Russian or
foreign scientific publications.
This scholarship is available to everyone
absolutely categories of graduate students,
regardless of whether you study on a budget
or on a contract form of training.
The amount of this scholarship varies.
So the scholarship of the President of the Russian
Federation is 4,500 rubles. monthly,
and a scholarship from the Russian Government
Federation is 3,600 rubles. monthly.
These scholarships are paid for the academic year.
At first glance you might think
that the size of these scholarships is insignificant.
However, they are very prestigious and if you
are a recipient of the Presidential Scholarship
or the Government of the Russian Federation,
then this is very honorable, very prestigious
and is considered one of the highest
forms of achievements of your science,
the research you
you are studying as a young scientist.
The next support measure, oh
which I will tell differs in that
that it is accessible to those
graduate students, those young scientists,
who are trained in priority areas
technological modernization
development of the Russian economy.
I'm talking about the scholarship of the President and the Government
just in priority areas.
Among other things, this scholarship
very important selection criterion
is your academic performance. You
must study "excellently"
and it must be at least 50
% of your overall performance.
You must also still have
outstanding achievements in scientific activity:
these are the same Olympiads, competitions,
receiving awards for research
the job you are doing.
These are patents, developments,
the grants you have
publications, speeches at
scientific conferences and so on.
An important difference of this scholarship
from the previous two is that
that your achievements are taken into account here
only in the last 2 years.
If the basic scholarships of the President and
Government of the Russian Federation
take into account all your research
activities since then
when you first started doing this,
then scholarships from the President and the Government
in priority areas
take into account your achievements
only in the last 2 years.
And the amount of these scholarships is like
you see, already much higher:
The President's stipend is
14,000 rub. monthly,
and a scholarship from the Russian Government
Federation is 10,000 rubles. monthly.
The next support measure I'll talk about is
are grants from the Russian Science Foundation
for the implementation of the Presidential
research project programs,
which are being implemented by our young scientists.
It is important to note here that in this Presidential
The program has two types of grants.
One of them is the so-called individual
competition - available to young scientists,
who are engaged in their
research alone.
And the second competition, which I’ll tell you about a little later,
available to research groups
under the guidance of young scientists.
And I’ll start with the basic grant, there’s more
some call it “my first grant” -
this is the implementation of the Presidential
research project programs,
which a young scientist can
implement it yourself.
To become a recipient
grant from the Russian Science Foundation,
you must have an advanced degree
candidate or doctor of sciences,
you should also have publications on
topic of the project, that is, on the topic
which you submit as part of this project to
various publications that are indexed,
or bibliographic databases, where
All our scientific publications are stored
(this is Web of Science, Scopus and so on,
or these are Russian sources, Russian bases
data, this is the RSCI you see on the screen).
Regarding the number of publications,
then to receive this grant
at least three publications are required,
but for humanitarian and social
sciences there is a small benefit,
and for representatives of precisely such sciences
only two publications required
in similar sources.
In addition, this project, which
you are applying for this competition,
should be aimed at solving specific
tasks within one of the priorities,
which are defined by the Strategy
scientific and technological
development of the Russian Federation.
This Strategy is available on the Internet,
you can always contact her
and check that direction
the research you are doing
how consistent it is with this Strategy.
The amount of this individual grant is
up to one and a half million and is paid annually.
More detailed information as per
grants from the Russian Science Foundation,
as well as for other support measures,
which I have talked about and will talk about
in this presentation, in this lecture,
you can check it out by going to
The QR code that is on these slides,
and find out more detailed information there.
Now let's talk about another grant
Russian Science Foundation,
which is already available for scientific
groups led by young scientists.
The requirements in this case are still
is the presence of an academic degree
from the leader of this team,
also the presence of publications in similar or
Russian or foreign databases,
but for scientific groups the leader of the scientific group
must already have at least five publications,
and for humanitarian and
social sciences - at least three.
It is important to understand that the leader
this competition, this project,
which you are submitting to the competition
Russian Science Foundation,
there must be a young scientist who is under 35 years old
(both for the first competition and for the second).
In our country, a young scientist is considered to be a person
who has not reached the age of 35 years inclusive.
Accordingly, you as a project manager
or an individual competition,
or a competition of small scientific groups
under the guidance of young scientists,
you must not be over 35 years old.
As before, the project within this
the competition must also be sent
to solve specific problems in
within one of the priorities,
which are determined by the same Strategy
scientific and technological development of our country.
The size of such a grant for small scientific
groups led by young scientists
already ranges from 3 to 5 million
rubles and is paid annually.
Another measure of support, oh
which I can’t help but tell you,
is the award of the President of the Russian Federation
in the field of science and innovation for young scientists.
This award is the highest form
gratitude in our country
and is handed over personally by the President into the hands of one or
several young scientists,
who receive this award.
Russian Presidential Award
Federation is appointed every year,
and you can apply every year
applications for this award.
Regarding the selection criteria, it is important to understand
that here you must already have outstanding
achievements in the field of science and technology,
which are confirmed by publications, patents
and in various other ways to show that
you are truly an outstanding young scientist,
that you have done a lot in
within the framework of its theme for our country,
for the development of science, for the development
innovation, technology and so on.
It is important to note that the recipients of this
prizes are usually scientists,
who are already close to the age of 35
years, since all those achievements
that you submit count towards your entire
scientific career, throughout your entire scientific life.
Accordingly, the older you are, the
your achievements are most likely greater.
The prize may be awarded
like one young scientist
(that is, you can only apply
from myself), and to a team of young scientists,
but in this team there should be
be no more than three people
and each member of the scientific team
must be up to 35 years of age inclusive.
In this case, you submit a collective application.
And, as practice shows, it is the collective
applications have a chance to win this award,
chances of receiving this award from
there are many more hands of the President,
than those scientists who apply individually.
The award amount is 5 million rubles
and the best thing about this award is that
that it is not subject to any taxes, and you
You get the full price fairly quickly.
The latest federal support measure
which I would like to tell you about today,
are public housing
certificates for young scientists.
Young scientist in order to get
this state housing certificate,
must also be no older than 35 years of age.
Among other things, he must, of course
same, have Russian citizenship,
work experience at a university or scientific organization
you must be at least five years old.
Of course you must have
PhD degree
and status in need of improvement
living conditions at the place of work.
It is important to note that the cost calculation
housing certificate varies.
It depends on in what
region is the organization
which puts you forward as
needing housing.
Calculation of the cost of this housing
certificate is produced
based on the size of the total area
living space of 33 sq.m.
and the average market value of one
square meter in that region,
where your organization is located.
If we are talking about Sverdlovsk
region, then we currently have
for 2023 the size of such a certificate
is approximately 3 million 300 thousand rubles.
With this certificate you can
use in several cases.
Firstly, you can use it to count
paying off a mortgage, for example, if you have one.
You can also use this certificate
as a down payment for
in order to take out a mortgage.
It is important to understand that this cost
is not given to you in cash,
that is, it is provided
exactly in the amount of the certificate,
which you give to the bank or to that organization,
which helps you decide
housing issue, if any.
And the validity period of the housing data
certificates is 3 months after
how are you officially appointed
recipient of this support measure.
Dear graduate students, young scientists!
It is important to note that those support measures
which I talked about
valid at the end of 2023.
In this area everything is very
changes quickly and very often,
so please, in order
to stay updated,
constantly understand what is happening, what is changing,
It is important for you to open the UrFU website, the “Science” section,
or go to the portal
youth science of our university
and keep track of all the relevant ones there
news, all the latest information,
which concerns the provision of support measures,
various - financial and non-financial,
which are available to our young scientists,
because everything changes very quickly.
And in order to stay informed,
the best option is to track
independently information on the UrFU website.