Hello, dear
listeners.
Today we'll talk
with you about
what a variety of shapes
can accept
in modern communication
scientific knowledge,
namely we will talk
about types of scientific articles.
In general, the production system
scientific knowledge
- this is a complex multidimensional
and a multifactorial process,
in which they take part
not only scientists or research teams,
but also members of the wider public:
states, business, industry and so on.
What role does it play in this?
Science Magazine?
As can be seen in the presented
picture,
scientific journal can be imagined
yourself with some kind of knot,
in the process of not only generation,
but also distribution
scientific knowledge among all
participants in this process.
Let's look at, let's say
So,
atomic level of this
process,
namely, a scientific article.
According to the definition, scientific
article
- this is a work of authorship,
published in a scientific journal
and describing the results
conducted research
using scientific methods.
Here I would like to draw
attention
on two very important points.
Firstly, this is copyright
work,
that is, every scientific
articles
there must be one authors
or several people.
Lately they've turned around
discussions:
Can it be considered artificial?
intelligence
co-author of a scientific article?
And a consensus has already been reached:
no, the authors can be
only people
which have and are determined
identity
and place of work, or is it
called affiliation.
In addition, scientific research
there must be
carried out using
scientific methods.
Are you already aware of philosophy?
studied or perhaps
you will study the principles
scientific method of cognition,
but here I will only mention
that any scientific knowledge
should match
criteria
reproducibility
and evidence.
Scientific article performs
essential functions
in the modern system.
Firstly, it is in the scientific
magazine
through the prism of a scientific article
generally just information
or is the data simply refracted?
and become scientific knowledge
through a certain
procedures,
which is called peer review.
This is an expert opinion
colleagues in this field.
Moreover, scientific knowledge
acquires
specific form via
that's how it will be
look on the pages
magazine.
And today we'll talk
about types of scientific articles.
Through scientific articles
and scientific journals
there is a process of accumulation
scientific knowledge,
as we all stand
so called,
on the shoulders of giants when
each subsequent knowledge
develops on the basis
already previous achievements, previous scientists.
Through a scientific article it is carried out
cycle,
when scientific knowledge spreads
Worldwide,
and anyone can
find such an article.
And finally, we must not forget
and about such an important function,
as an attribution of scientific
knowledge, authorship,
because scientists need
prioritize your achievements,
and it happens
namely through publication.
Therefore we can summarize
and say,
what is a scientific article anyway?
must correspond
the following most important criteria.
First, in a scientific article
there must be novelty
that is, the knowledge that
made available to the public
must be reported in this
work for the first time
and wear very important
significant methodological character.
In addition, scientists should
use
namely the scientific method of cognition -
this is experience, theorizing, building models.
Finally, no review
it will just be information
but by no means scientific
article.
And finally - and this is very important
for our discussion today -
scientific work is being written
in a scientific style of speech,
which is characterized
the presence of special terminology,
sequence
and logic of presentation
and also the severity of style.
Currently already established
three main types of scientific articles:
this is original research
article,
so-called original research
paper or article,
review article
or paper
and finally short messages
or short communications.
In English here
these two words article and paper -
they are practically interchangeable,
and it depends on the style of the magazine,
from the tastes of the editors, like
call
article in this particular
magazine.
But it is important to note that everything
these are the three types of articles
found in the form of rubrics
international scientific information databases
and national databases (such as
as RSCI, RSCI),
and international (Scopus or
Web of Science).
If you open any
from these databases,
you will see this important
category:
origin research paper, review paper
or short messages.
Let's take a closer look
let's look at each of these types
and their characteristic features.
And we will begin, of course,
from original research article,
because she is the one
today, let's say
currency of scientific communication,
they should be the majority
every self-respecting scientist has
that is, of course, review articles,
and short messages.
But it is precisely in the track record
more products produced
- these are the original ones
articles.
This is the first performance
results to the scientific community,
so just for this
type of articles
The criteria for plagiarism are very
strict.
And when they ask: “How much
Is it possible to plagiarize - 20 or 30%?”,
doesn't really work here
talking about percentages
because borrowing,
their number
should tend to zero
Ideally.
Moreover, in the original
research articles
must be present
clear consistent
and a clear description of the methodology
research,
that is, how they were received
results.
This is necessary in order to
to achieve reproducibility of results,
so that other scientists can
repeat your research
or your logic of reasoning
and get approximately the same results.
Articles like this
as a rule,
differ empirically
character,
that is, as a rule, in empirical
sciences specifically
original research
articles and distributed.
It is important that the scientific article
cannot be considered
scientific without a list of references,
that is, without a list of those sources
on which the reasoning is based,
logics
or is it built on its own?
study.
Finally, it is important to note
we will talk about it
in another video, but not anyway
less,
that, as a rule, these are the original ones
research articles today in the 21st century
followed almost everywhere
format - the so-called IMRAD -
– this is the format when the article
divided into introduction,
methods, results
and discussion of the results.
Let's see for example
performance
original research
articles in a scientific journal.
Here, please do not delve into
to the essence of the study,
without reading the language.
I just want to demonstrate
how important is structuring
such articles.
Look, it's quite
Annotations are clearly visible,
required inside the article
there are sections -
like larger materials
methods, results,
so definitely some
subsections.
This is of course necessary
to speed up the healing of information,
that is, we make it easier in every possible way
life
our potential
readers and reviewers
in order to do
material
as accessible as possible.
And, in the end, we definitely see
bibliography,
which becomes
more and more.
If earlier an approximate list
literature
included 12, maybe 14
sources,
then today we see 50,
and 60,
and in review articles, of course,
and even more.
So let's just talk
about the review article - review.
Their importance especially increases
in the last 20-30 years,
and this is due to the fact that
that the volume of scientific knowledge
grows every year
in incredible progression
geometric or what
whatever it was.
However, some
see and talk about
that the volume of knowledge doubles,
others say it triples,
Certainly,
quite difficult to calculate.
And review articles - they are intended
precisely for this purpose
to do an analysis
already published works,
so-called meta-analysis
and through critical analysis
achievements in a certain
fields of knowledge
for a certain period
identify
trends, gaps
in existing knowledge
in order to be able
scientists
give absolutely clear
ways of directions where to develop further.
And a review article is a must
is based on a strict methodology,
that is, it cannot be considered
for quality reviews,
when it's just going
transfer
some research or other
in one area or another.
Of course this cannot be considered
quality review,
this is definitely clear
Source selection methodology.
And in connection with the fact,
that the methodologies are different,
different research goals,
In fact,
inside this review genre
there are quite a lot
wide species diversity,
that is, there are quite a lot of types, reviews.
And you and I, let's take a look
by three, let's say
basic, common
type.
We can expect
what's coming soon
new types of reviews
will spread more and more
but nonetheless,
So let's look at three.
First of all, this is what is called
narrative review or narrative review,
and its meaning is... Undoubtedly,
Have you come across reviews like this?
most likely, you yourself
wrote them
in some coursework
works, theses,
because it's pretty
general and schematic
research descriptions
on a certain issue.
Typically, for data
reviews
not expected to be strict
source selection algorithm,
and the significance of this kind
reviews
as separate publications
very low.
Many magazines are already stopping
accept
for consideration of this kind
reviews.
But nevertheless they are still
are important
as part of larger
research.
For example, when writing
original research articles
produced exactly the same way
review of literature in this area,
sometimes it is carried out in such
articles in a separate subsection.
And, of course, narrative
reviews
can't be compared
with these kinds of reviews,
which are called systematic
reviews or systematic review.
Already used here
very clear and precise methodology
and scientists put specific
research questions.
In this systematic
review implies
not just quantitative
counting how many articles
was published
on one issue or another,
in such and such databases
or magazines
with one or another quartile,
but deep reading is implied
the sources themselves,
deep analysis of them.
Therefore, scientists who
publish a systematic review,
it is assumed that they
studied
every detail and depth
article,
which they include
to review.
And finally, there's more
such a new direction -
so-called subject review
fields or scoping review,
and unlike systematic
review
it's much wider here
coverage of sources.
These types of reviews can
include
both 200 and 300 sources
and analyze them.
And the purpose of this kind of reviews
– establish the boundaries of the subject field
by search, continuous
searching for sources -
be it national bases,
international bases,
that is, it is desirable
so that scientists can
gain access
to the largest possible
variety of articles published.
And then it is produced according to
methodology,
classification, systematization,
categorization,
deep data analysis
sources.
Currently like this
kind of reviews,
they are also widely used
and are very, very appreciated.
It must be said that in Russia
review articles
as a species, as a separate genre,
as a separate type
are already starting to spread
actively.
And look, many
researchers
follow exactly this one
logic,
when first determine
research questions,
then they make a selection
research
taking into account certain criteria,
and then determine the direction of development.
Look, in this
case with us...
We see with you that scientists
not only just take away,
carry out quantitative
assessment,
but also deep quality
analysis.
And finally, let's move on
to a short message.
This is also very important
and a rapidly developing genre
scientific articles,
type of scientific articles.
There are different names
you will see not only short communications,
you will see this section
like letters - letters
or commentaries - comments,
but nevertheless, one way or another
otherwise,
this is absolutely certain
type of study,
when scientists for some reason
reasons
need it quickly
report that
that they noticed something
outstanding effect.
And in this case, in order to
to fix
your priority for this
acquired knowledge,
it makes sense to publish
such,
so-called short
message.
Brief messages in comparison
with original articles
are cited more
this has already been proven,
and there are even some
satellite magazines
to the main large magazines,
which publish only
short messages.
Definitely this kind
content is reviewed,
that is, exactly the same
like any scientific article,
they are very exposed
strict analysis procedure,
they also contain lists
literature.
And here's an interesting point:
that the number of references,
number of sources
on the list
often comparable to full-fledged ones
big articles.
Of course, just like the word says
"short message"
this kind of publication
smaller in size.
If the usual original
research article
may include 40-50
thousand characters or 5-6 thousand words,
then short messages are
usually 2-3 thousand words,
but nevertheless, they also include figures and tables,
and the same requirements apply to them,
as for traditional work,
namely relevance,
novelty, significance.
In Russia short messages
are also starting to develop
and on this slide you see
magazine article
"University management:
practice and analysis",
where they are published in the section
"Cases of best practices"
essentially short messages.
We see with you what is here
There is also an annotation
and also inside the article itself
division occurs
or separate
subheadings, introductions, and so on.
Where can we even be with you?
look,
Here we are preparing our publication,
what type of article to choose,
Which genre does it fit into?
our scientific research?
And in this case
will help you and me
instructions for authors
in a scientific journal.
She is the one
the most important source of information.
Many editors complain
that authors submit articles
for consideration, preliminary
without reading the instructions for authors,
which definitely exists
on the website of any scientific journal.
Why is it important?
Because it's in the instructions
for authors reported
about what topics you are interested in
magazine,
what types of articles,
be it review articles
either original or short
messages
more interested in this
specific edition.
The point is that there are some
magazines,
which publish only
reviews,
but there is, as I already mentioned,
magazines,
which publish only
short messages,
therefore, this is very important
study the instructions,
before submitting yours
work for this magazine.
In addition, in this section
reported
about the review policy,
how long does it take,
how many reviewers research
article,
who can be considered the author,
and who cannot be considered the author.
Let me give you an example:
can he be considered the author?
scientific article
translator, for example,
From Russian into English
language,
who translated this article?
That is, this is also regulated
everything is in the instructions for authors.
Some magazines offer
paid services,
for example, by design
lists of references,
and in this case in the instructions
this is also discussed.
And finally, important information
About,
in what style to present
bibliography
and format this
manuscript.
It would be wrong to think
that publication of a scientific article
– it’s a quick and simple process,
when we submit our article
and within a month we see her
on the pages of magazines.
Unfortunately, it is not.
This process takes
for a long time,
it could be six months,
maybe even a year.
Of course, publishing houses
where exists
very effective business model
(for example, publishing house
MDPI) -
this process is reduced
up to a month, or even two,
but nevertheless the logic of passage
articles
remains approximately the same.
Let's take a look at it.
First, scientists submit their
manuscript.
Actually at this stage
can't talk yet
that this is a scientific article,
most likely this is a manuscript
for consideration in this
magazine.
And first the editors, as well
special machine systems
are researching this article
and may be rejected due to
Togo,
that she doesn't match
subject matter
or the authors are not enough
attentively
read the instructions for
authors in this journal.
And they may reject
according to other formal requirements -
for example, a list of references
presented incorrectly
and of course
if the borrowing level
in this article exceeds
stipulated limits,
then in this case, of course,
the article is rejected.
But if the manuscript
this rough sieve has passed through,
then the process happens
the so-called review
in English it's called
peer review.
In this case, this work
sent to reviewers.
In this case, two are depicted,
but actually
it could be one reviewer,
if the area is very narrow.
Or maybe, on the contrary,
be three or even more reviewers.
In my practice I once
faced with a situation
when the magazine used
12 reviewers.
Their task is to analyze
read the article carefully
and give your conclusion
about its quality.
Naturally, at the forefront -
scientific quality.
Reviewers report
about your decision
editor-in-chief,
which, taking into account
and weighing various factors,
makes a decision -
or reject the article,
or send for revision.
In general, in principle,
there is a third option,
when the article is accepted
without comments,
but it happens like this
it's rare that even
usually does not turn on
into algorithms,
in the description of the publication process.
After finalizing the article
authors
send it back to the editor,
and this circle can repeat itself
two or three times until
editor-in-chief for now
will not consider this article
suitable for publication,
what the authors are informed about
And then it happens
the publishing process itself,
and this is where the manuscript is already
becomes a scientific article.
So, we've talked
and looked
for different types of scientific
articles.
And I hope that this
the information will be useful to you,
when you search
ideal article type
for your spent
research.
Thank you.