Good afternoon, dear colleagues!
Today we will talk about modern methods for assessing the scientific performance of a scientist.
The question may arise: who and why needs to evaluate a scientist’s scientific performance?
There can be many answers to this question - including his own administration,
scientific supervisor and other interested organizations and individuals.
But we will talk about the main thing for graduate students and researchers -
reasons why we should be concerned about evaluating our scientific performance.
We all, I think, participate or want to participate in scientific grants.
Now, if we look at the application for a grant from the Russian Science Foundation (the main scientific fund
in the field of natural sciences and engineering),
then in each application it is mandatory when submitting the scientific team of this application
indicates the planned results of the project.
In particular, the number of publications that will be published in journals
from the Web of Science, Scopus database,
in the database of the Russian Science Citation Index, or eLibrary,
and in publications indexed in other databases.
We also immediately describe in which journals we plan to publish our work
and to which quartile, by which indicator these journals belong.
As a result, after completing the project, a scientific report is generated,
in which we ourselves fill out the list of published works.
They are automatically divided into categories,
whether they belong to Web of Science, Scopus, which quartiles, and so on.
Based on this list, the following statistical table is formed:
which is presented on the slide.
It compares the planned indicators of the application with actual indicators
for each year of the project.
The second example of an assessment that we are subject to is the Priority 2030 program.
It is known that the Ural Federal University is an active participant
federal program "Priority 2030" for the development of the scientific component of universities.
The rules of this program were approved by order of the Ministry of Science and Higher Education
Russian Federation dated May 31, 2021 and are still in effect.
In particular, these rules indicate two main scientific indicators
is the number of publications in scientific journals
first and second quartiles based on Web of Science data.
The second indicator is the number of publications,
indexed in the Scopus database and classified in the first and second quartiles of SNIP.
That is, the first indicator is calculated according to the impact factor from Web of Science,
the second indicator is based on SNIP from the Scopus database.
And joint publications are necessarily taken into account based on the fractional counting method.
That is, if an article has several authors, each of these authors has several affiliations,
then the organization is awarded only a fraction of the point for each publication.
What is SNIP?
This is the source-normalized impact factor of an article.
The indicator was proposed by Elsevier,
allows you to compare sources from different subject areas
and evaluate journal impact in citation weighting.
compared to the total number of citations in the subject area.
Its numerator is the average number of links,
and the denominator is the average citation in the subject area.
Thus, we can easily compare different subject areas with each other.
Fractional counting is a method of counting co-authored scientific articles.
where are taken into account as shares of the article,
which are distributed between organizations from different affiliations,
and the author's share, which depends on the number of authors in the article.
The factional score is calculated using this formula, that is, the sum of factional points
cannot exceed one for each article and in total for the organization
the sum is calculated for all authors,
for all affiliations, taking into account the factional account of the level of authors.
From the rector's report for 2022 we see
that in our Ural Federal University there are approximately 1,000 more publications
only a little over 300,
that is, approximately 1/3 of the points are due to the University on the factional score.
The rest relates either to other organizations of the Russian Federation,
or to international partners.
On what basis do we ourselves or our partners
can funds or administration evaluate our scientometric indicators?
Let's move on to a practical level and look at the data sources for such an assessment.
So, where can you find information about your own publications and scientometric indicators?
Naturally, history can and should be preserved
of their publications on paper or in electronic formats.
However, it is convenient to search in electronic database systems,
such as, for example, the electronic scientific library eLibrary.ru.
Here we can go to the directory of authors, and by last name
(I will use my last name throughout for simplicity),
You can find your own person by last name, especially if you are registered in the system.
For example, Evgeniy Aleksandrovich Buntov and by clicking on the list of his publications